Guide to the Lee De Forest Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Lee De Forest papers
1896-1971
MS 1210
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1
Largely writings of Lee De Forest including typescripts of his diary, of his published autobiography, and of an article on turbines. The small amount of his correspondence includes a series of letters to Jessica Wallace Millar.
De Forest, Lee, 1873-1961
Immediate Source of Acquisition
In part, gift of Hope M. Scrogin, 1973.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Lee De Forest Papers contain a small amount of correspondence. Most of it is letters from De Forest and his wife Marie Mosquini to Mrs. Jessica (Wallace) Millar, De Forest's "first love," as described in Chapter 8 of his autobiography, Father of Radio. There is also correspondence with a few other friends, and several Yale University letters concerning a testimonial dinner and bust of De Forest.
Over two thirds of the collection consists of writings by De Forest. Included are two versions of his autobiography, as well as a copy of the published volume. Also in the collection are a number of newspaper clippings about De Forest and several miscellaneous items.
Biographical / Historical
Lee De Forest was born in Council Bluffs, Iowa, on August 26, 1873. He was a graduate of the Sheffield Scientific School at Yale University in 1896 and received a Ph.D. from Yale in 1899. He was an important contributor in the development of wireless telegraphy in the United States. He started multiple radio broadcasting companies and patented 300 inventions in his lifetime. In 1904, he was awarded the gold medal at the World's Fair in St. Louis, Missouri. He died on June 30, 1961.
Turbines; Autobiographies; Diaries; Inventors; De Forest, Lee, 1873-1961; Millar, Jessica Wallace
- Inventory
  - Correspondence
    - Millar, Mrs. Jessica Wallace, 1950-1959, undated (Box 1, Folder 1 - 2)
    - Scrogin, Hope (Mrs. Frank), 1950-1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Wallace Ida B., 1911, 1927, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Wallace, W. W., 1901 October 3
    - Yale University, 1952-1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Writings
    - "The De Laval Steam Turbine, and Other Turbines" (typescript), [1896?] (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "The Diaries of Doctor De Forest" (typescript), pp. 1-200, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 7 - 8)
    - "The Diaries of Doctor De Forest" (typescript), pp. 201-476, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 9 - 11)
    - Father of Radio: Autobiography of Lee De Forest
      - Typescript, pp. 1-700, [1948?] (Box 2, Folder 12 - 18)
      - Typescript, pp. 701-1166, appendices, [1948?] (Box 3, Folder 19 - 24)
      - Published volume, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Newspaper clippings and printed matter relating to Lee De Forest, 1946-1966, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous, 1952, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)